"use strict";(self.webpackChunklearning=self.webpackChunklearning||[]).push([[44],{44:(e,t,i)=>{i.r(t),i.d(t,{gramma:()=>n});i(43);const n=[{semester:1,grade:8,questions:[{id:41,extra:"<p><b>Exercise 1: Fill in the correct form of the word in parentheses</b></p>",question:"She enjoys (read) \u2026\u2026\u2026. books in her free time. \n            ",options:[],answer:"reading",lastwrite:"",explanation:"<p>enjoy + V_ing</p>"},{id:41,extra:"",question:"The question is easy _____ (answer).\n            ",options:[],answer:"to answer",rewrite:"",lastwrite:"",explanation:"To Infinitive l\xe0m t\xe2n ng\u1eef c\u1ee7a t\xednh t\u1eeb."},{id:41,extra:"",question:"They practiced (sing) \u2026\u2026\u2026. together before the performance.\n            ",options:[],answer:"singing",rewrite:"",lastwrite:"",explanation:"practice + V_ing"},{id:41,extra:"",question:"The man asked me how _____ (get) to the airport.\n            ",options:[],answer:"to get",rewrite:"",lastwrite:"",explanation:"To Infinitive l\xe0m t\xe2n ng\u1eef ch\u1ec9 ng\u01b0\u1eddi"},{id:41,extra:"",question:"The teacher expected Sarah _____ (study) hard.\n            ",options:[],answer:"to study",rewrite:"",lastwrite:"",explanation:"To Infinitive l\xe0m t\xe2n ng\u1eef ch\u1ec9 ng\u01b0\u1eddi"},{id:41,extra:"",question:"I suggest (visit) \u2026\u2026\u2026. the museum while you\u2019re in town.\n            ",options:[],answer:"visiting",rewrite:"",lastwrite:"",explanation:"suggest + V_ing: "},{id:41,extra:"",question:"I learned _____ (ride) the bike at the age of 5\n            ",options:[],answer:"to ride",rewrite:"",lastwrite:"",explanation:"Learn to + V:\tH\u1ecdc \u0111\u1ec3 l\xe0m \u0111i\u1ec1u g\xec \u0111\xf3"},{id:41,extra:"",question:"He admitted (cheat) \u2026\u2026\u2026. on the test.\n            ",options:[],answer:"cheating",rewrite:"",lastwrite:"",explanation:"admitted + V_ing: th\u1eeba nh\u1eadn"},{id:41,extra:"",question:"We\u2019re considering (take) \u2026\u2026\u2026. a trip to the mountains next weekend.\n            ",options:[],answer:"taking",rewrite:"",lastwrite:"",explanation:"consider + V_ing: c\xe2n nh\u1eafc, xem x\xe9t"},{id:41,extra:"",question:" It was a nice day, so we decided ________ for a walk. (go)\n            ",options:[],answer:"to go",rewrite:"",lastwrite:"",explanation:"Decide to + V:\tQuy\u1ebft \u0111\u1ecbnh l\xe0m g\xec"},{id:41,extra:"",question:"Have you ever thought about (learn) \u2026\u2026\u2026. a new language?\n            ",options:[],answer:"learning",rewrite:"",lastwrite:"",explanation:"thought about + V_ing: suy ngh\u0129 v\u1ec1 vi\u1ec7c g\xec \u0111\xf3"},{id:41,extra:"",question:"They don\u2019t have much money. They can\u2019t afford __________ out very often. (go)\n            ",options:[],answer:"to go",rewrite:"",lastwrite:"",explanation:"Afford to + V: \tChi tr\u1ea3 cho vi\u1ec7c g\xec"},{id:41,extra:"",question:"She avoids (eat) \u2026\u2026\u2026. junk food for better health.\n            ",options:[],answer:"eating",rewrite:"",lastwrite:"",explanation:"avoid + V_ing: tr\xe1nh l\xe0m g\xec \u0111\xf3"},{id:41,extra:"",question:"They discussed (start) \u2026\u2026\u2026. a new business venture.\n            ",options:[],answer:"starting",rewrite:"",lastwrite:"",explanation:"discussed + V_ing: th\u1ea3o lu\u1eadn v\u1ec1 vi\u1ec7c g\xec \u0111\xf3"},{id:41,extra:"",question:"Our neighbour threatened __________ the police if we didn\u2019t stop the noise. (call)\n            ",options:[],answer:"to call",rewrite:"",lastwrite:"",explanation:"threatened to + V: \u0111e d\u1ecda l\xe0m g\xec \u0111\xf3"},{id:41,extra:"",question:"Are you interested in (join) \u2026\u2026\u2026. the club?\n            ",options:[],answer:"joining",rewrite:"",lastwrite:"",explanation:"interested in + V_ing: quan t\xe2m \u0111\u1ebfn vi\u1ec7c g\xec \u0111\xf3, V_ing theo sao gi\u1edbi t\u1eeb"},{id:41,extra:"",question:"Hurry up! I don\u2019t want to risk ____________ the rain. (miss)\n            ",options:[],answer:"missing",rewrite:"",lastwrite:"",explanation:"risk + V_ing: m\u1ea1o hi\u1ec3m l\xe0m g\xec \u0111\xf3"},{id:41,extra:"",question:"He apologized for (arrive) \u2026\u2026\u2026. late to the meeting.\n            ",options:[],answer:"arriving",rewrite:"",lastwrite:"",explanation:"apologized for + V_ing: xin l\u1ed7i v\u1ec1 vi\u1ec7c g\xec \u0111\xf3, V_ing theo sao gi\u1edbi t\u1eeb"}]},{semester:1,grade:8,questions:[{id:41,extra:"<p><b>Exercise 2: Choose the correct answer</b></p>",question:"The children enjoy \u2026\u2026\u2026. stories before bedtime.\n            ",options:["reading","to read","read","reads"],answer:"1",rewrite:"",lastwrite:"",explanation:"enjoy + V_ing: th\xedch l\xe0m g\xec \u0111\xf3"},{id:41,extra:"",question:"She avoids \u2026\u2026\u2026. out late at night alone.\n            ",options:["go","going","to go","goes"],answer:"2",rewrite:"",lastwrite:"",explanation:"avoid + V_ing: tr\xe1nh l\xe0m g\xec \u0111\xf3"},{id:41,extra:"",question:"We discussed the possibility of \u2026\u2026\u2026. a trip to Europe next summer.\n            ",options:["take","taking","to take","takes"],answer:"2",rewrite:"",lastwrite:"",explanation:"Gerund theo sau gi\u1edbi t\u1eeb"},{id:41,extra:"",question:"I dream about ______ a big house.\n            ",options:["To build","build","building"],answer:"3",rewrite:"",lastwrite:"",explanation:"sau gi\u1edbi t\u1eeb about l\xe0 V_ing"},{id:41,extra:"",question:"She doesn't mind ________ the night shift.\n            ",options:["Working","to work","work"],answer:"1",rewrite:"",lastwrite:"",explanation:"mind + V_ing: kh\xf4ng phi\u1ec1n l\xe0m g\xec \u0111\xf3"},{id:41,extra:"",question:"The man asked me how ______ to the airport.\n            ",options:["To get","getting","get"],answer:"1",rewrite:"",lastwrite:"",explanation:"ask + somebody + to V: h\u1ecfi ai \u0111\xf3 l\xe0m g\xec"},{id:41,extra:"",question:"He agreed _______ a new car.\n            ",options:["To buy","Buying","buy"],answer:"1",rewrite:"",lastwrite:"",explanation:"agree + to V"},{id:41,extra:"",question:"I look forward to ______ you at the weekend.\n            ",options:["See","Seeing","to see"],answer:"2",rewrite:"",lastwrite:"",explanation:"sau gi\u1edbi t\u1eeb to"}]},{semester:1,grade:8,questions:[{id:41,extra:"<p><b>Rewrite the sentences</b></p>",question:"I like making crafts especially bracelet.\n            ",options:[],answer:"making crafts especially bracelet",rewrite:"I enjoy",lastwrite:"",explanation:"enjoy + V_ing"},{id:41,extra:"",question:"Minh doesn't like making models because it is very boring.\n            ",options:[],answer:"making models because it is very boring",rewrite:"Minh detests",lastwrite:"",explanation:"detest + V_ing: get l\xe0m g\xec"},{id:41,extra:"",question:"My brother likes making pottery because it is a creative activity.\n            ",options:[],answer:"on making pottery because it is a creative activity",rewrite:"My brother is hooked",lastwrite:"",explanation:"hooked on + V_ing: very interested in / addicted to / really enjoys: r\u1ea5t th\xedch"},{id:41,extra:"",question:"We enjoy doing gardening because it is very relaxing.\n            ",options:[],answer:"on doing gardening because it is very relaxing",rewrite:"We are keen",lastwrite:"",explanation:'"keen on" = interested in / enthusiastic about / enjoy + V_ing'},{id:41,extra:"",question:"Shall we go for a walk?\n            ",options:[],answer:"going for a walk",rewrite:"What about",lastwrite:"",explanation:"What about + V_ing"},{id:41,extra:"",question:"Why don\u2019t we visit our teacher?\n            ",options:[],answer:"visiting our teacher",rewrite:"I suggest ",lastwrite:"",explanation:"suggest + V_ing"},{id:41,extra:"",question:" I am very pleased that we shall meet again soon\n            ",options:[],answer:"forward to our meeting again soon.",rewrite:"I\u2019m looking",lastwrite:"",explanation:"Look forward to+ V_ing: mong ch\u1edd, h\xe1o h\u1ee9c v\u1ec1 \u0111i\u1ec1u g\xec, vi\u1ec7c g\xec \u0111\xf3"},{id:41,extra:"",question:"It is really quite easy to learn English\n            ",options:[],answer:"really quite easy.",rewrite:"Learning English is ",lastwrite:"",explanation:"Ving \u0111\u1ee9ng \u0111\u1ea7u c\xe2u \u0111\xf3ng vai tr\xf2 ch\u1ee7 ng\u1eef<br/>Learning English is + O"},{id:41,extra:"",question:"Complaining about the matter is useless now.\n            ",options:[],answer:"useless to complain about the matter.",rewrite:"It is",lastwrite:"",explanation:" It+ be+ adj+ to V: th\u1eadt... \u0111\u1ec3 l\xe0m g\xec (useless)"},{id:41,extra:"",question:"I don\u2019t want to go to the movie tonight\n            ",options:[],answer:"going to the movie theater tonight.",rewrite:"I don\u2019t feel like",lastwrite:"",explanation:"like + V_ing"}]},{semester:1,grade:8,questions:[{id:41,extra:"<p><b>Gerund or Infinitive \u2013 Fill in the correct form.</b></p>",question:"They are likely __________________ up at any time. (show)\n            ",options:[],answer:"to show",rewrite:"",lastwrite:"",explanation:"sau t\xednh t\u1eeb likely + to V"},{id:41,extra:"",question:"The man denied __________ the crime. (commit)\n            ",options:[],answer:"committing",rewrite:"",lastwrite:"",explanation:"deny + V_ing"},{id:41,extra:"",question:"Their memories of ____________ in Africa will stay with them forever. (travel)\n            ",options:[],answer:"traveling",rewrite:"",lastwrite:"",explanation:"sau gi\u1edbi t\u1eeb of + V_ing"},{id:41,extra:"",question:"He has always been afraid of ____________. (fly)\n            ",options:[],answer:"flying",rewrite:"",lastwrite:"",explanation:"sau gi\u1edbi t\u1eeb of + V_ing"},{id:41,extra:"",question:"____________ is good for your health. (swim)\n            ",options:[],answer:"Swimming",rewrite:"",lastwrite:"",explanation:"Gerund Th\u01b0\u1eddng \u0111\u01b0\u1ee3c s\u1eed d\u1ee5ng khi h\xe0nh \u0111\u1ed9ng l\xe0 c\xf3 th\u1eadt<br/>Gerund l\xe0m ch\u1ee7 ng\u1eef trong c\xe2u"},{id:41,extra:"",question:"She promised _______________ the report as soon as possible. (read)\n            ",options:[],answer:"to read",rewrite:"",lastwrite:"",explanation:"Promise to:\tH\u1ee9a h\u1eb9n l\xe0m g\xec"},{id:41,extra:"",question:"I had a hard time ____________ the situation to my husband. (explain)\n            ",options:[],answer:"explaining",rewrite:"",lastwrite:"",explanation:"C\u1ea5u tr\xfac: having a hard time: \u0111\u1ec3 n\xf3i cho ai \u0111\xf3 bi\u1ebft r\u1eb1ng b\u1ea1n \u0111ang g\u1eb7p kh\xf3 kh\u0103n \u0111\u1ec3 l\xe0m m\u1ed9t vi\u1ec7c g\xec \u0111\xf3<br>have difficulty / trouble / a hard time / problems + verb-ing"},{id:41,extra:"",question:"She had some problems ____________ without glasses. (read)\n            ",options:[],answer:"reading",rewrite:"",lastwrite:"",explanation:"have difficulty / trouble / a hard time / problems + verb-ing"},{id:41,extra:"",question:"Paul gave up _____________ five years ago. (smoke)\n            ",options:[],answer:"smoking",rewrite:"",lastwrite:"",explanation:"sau gi\u1edbi t\u1eeb +V_ing"},{id:41,extra:"",question:"Most teachers insist on their pupils ______________ (do) the homework.\n            ",options:[],answer:"doing",rewrite:"",lastwrite:"",explanation:"insist on + noun / pronoun + verb-ing"},{id:41,extra:"",question:"She has often made me ______________ (cry).\n            ",options:[],answer:"cry",rewrite:"",lastwrite:"",explanation:'"make" + object + base verb (bare infinitive \u2014 without \u201cto\u201d)<br>After verbs like make, let, and help, when followed by an object, we usually use the base form of the verb (not to + verb or verb-ing).'},{id:41,extra:"",question:" I expect ____________ (hear) from you by Monday.\n            ",options:[],answer:"to hear",rewrite:"",lastwrite:"",explanation:"Expect sb to:\tK\xec v\u1ecdng ai l\xe0m g\xec"},{id:41,extra:"",question:"I can't make a decision. I keep ______________ (change) my mind.\n            ",options:[],answer:"changing",rewrite:"",lastwrite:"",explanation:"Keep+ V_ing:\tgi\u1eef"},{id:41,extra:"",question:"He had made his decision and refused ___________ (change) his mind.\n            ",options:[],answer:"to change",rewrite:"",lastwrite:"",explanation:"Refuse + to Verb: t\u1eeb ch\u1ed1i c\xe1i g\xec"},{id:41,extra:"",question:"When I finish (prepare) ________the food, I'll set the table.\n            ",options:[],answer:"preparing",rewrite:"",lastwrite:"",explanation:"finish + V_ing: k\u1ebft th\xfac l\xe0m g\xec"},{id:41,extra:"",question:"Do you know how (fix) ________ the screen?\n            ",options:[],answer:"to fix",rewrite:"",lastwrite:"",explanation:"know how + to + verb: bi\u1ebft l\xe0m g\xec"}]}]}}]);
//# sourceMappingURL=44.cbcb91ca.chunk.js.map